A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Log Files (Grant and Project Proposals) FA734
Rockefeller Archive Center
- 1984
  - L84-300: Educational Program for the Individual in Community, South Africa: Support for publications, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-302: Columbia University: Human Rights summer internships and visiting students program, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-303: University of Monash, Australia: National barriers to international trade, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-305: University of Iowa: Support for the international writing program to bring writers from poorer countries to the U.S., 1984 (Reel L-541)
  - L84-306: Ford Foundation: Gifts to the Foundation, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-307: International Council for Adult Education: General file on women's issues, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-311: Ford Foundation: Nairobi meeting on social agro-forestry in 1985, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-314: Ford Foundation: Nairobi proposal rejects re: women conference in spring 1985, 1984 (Reel L-541)
  - L84-317: Democratic Lawyers Association, South Africa: Facilitate professional legal services for community organizations, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-320: Rouna Q Jahan (Bangladesh): National machineries: Women's ghetto or instruments of power, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-324: Planeconomicn, Inc: Construction and maintenance of east European economic data banks, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-328: Tufts University (MASS): 1. Income and wasting assets 2. economic teaching for diplomats, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-329: McLean and Company. Ltd.: Study of counter-trade and third world development, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-330: Southern African Arts Trust Fund: Memorialize and publicize the proceedings of the cultural and resistance festival of southern Africa, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-331: Christian Relief and Development Association: Provide services of senior social science advisor, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-333: University of Pittsburgh: Conference on Thirty years after: the development and impact of events in 1956 in eastern Europe, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-335: Agrarian Research and Training Institute: Regional seminar on irrigation management, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-336: International Water Resources Association: 5th World Congress on Water Resources, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-340: West Virginia University: Women and Rural Development, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-341: Brookings Institution: Impediments to European growth, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-344: International Bar Association, England: Educational programs, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-346: Republic of Kenya: Study of local food security systems, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-347: Ford Foundation: Tour of Indian water management training and research activities, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-348: Ford Foundation: Human rights and rural poverty, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-349: University of Dayton: Effect of decline of U.S. dominance on it's participation in international organizations, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-350: California Coastal, Rural Development Corp: Employment of Hispanics and Asian migrants, 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-351: Rand Corporation: Western economic leverage on the U.S.S.R., 1984 (Reel L-513)
  - L84-352: Universidad Autonoma de Canto Blanco, Spain: Research and training in strategic studies, 1984 (Reel L-513)
- 1985
  - L85-2: Ford Foundation: Population: New Programs (see PA86-774 and PA 86-752), 1985 (Reel L-499)
  - L85-4: Resources for the Future, Inc.: Value of capital losses by north American Indian tribes, 1985 (Reel L-498)
  - L85-7: Harvard University: Develop guidelines to redesign relief programs into long-term developmental ones, 1985 (Reel L-498)
  - L85-10: Ford Foundation: Workshops, conferences and meetings for EC Program for 1985 (Reel L-498)
  - L85-14: Ford Foundation: Pre-school educational and childcare group, 1985 (Reel L-498)
  - L85-15: Australian National University: Conference in industrialization in east and southeast Asia, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-16: Foundation for Peace and Justice, South Africa: Black leadership development, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-18: Foundation for Women Judges: Provide education and supportive programs to women judges and to develop programs directed to the women in the judiciary, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-24: U.N. Research Institute for Social Development: Survey on social conditions of refugees of Central America, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-29: Center for Economic Policy Research: C.E.P.R. Menu, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-30: New York University: Center for the study of war, peace and the news media, 1985 (Reel L-520)
  - L85-34: University of California/ Los Angeles: Security economics, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-35: George Washington University: Japanese investment in the U.S. auto industry, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-36: Consultative Group for International Agricultural Research: Private sector funding project, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-39: Evergreen State College, Olympia, Washington: To create the Washington State Center for Improvement of Quality of Undergraduate Education, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-42: Columbia University: Establish 5-year joint degree program for minorities in liberal arts and urban planning, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-43: International Council for Equality of Opportunity Principles, Inc.: economic, social and political freedom of blacks in South Africa, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-45: World Federation of Public Health Associations: Proposal for a center on women and health, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-46: Harvard University: Conference on Unemployment in the Great Depression, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-47: Montclair State College: Summer institute for the W.C.C.T.O.P. college, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-52: Women's International Information and Communication Service, Switzerland: Background file, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-54: All Indian Pueblo Council, Inc.: Create a pueblo water management institute, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-55: Gila River Farms, Arizona: Support for economic development of the GILA River Indian community, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-58: University of Wisconsin: American Indian social welfare policy, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-61: Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey: Study to analyze the impact of the pregnancy discrimination act of 1978, 1985 (Reel L-500)
  - L85-63: MacArthur Foundation: Fellowship program in international security, 1985 (Reel L-501)
  - L85-67: Ford Foundation: Ford Foundation regarding: Background on refugee assistance organization, 1985 (Reel L-501)
  - L85-69: American Association of State Colleges: Identify, validate and disseminate model practices of TOP's among urban higher education institutions, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-70: Federation for the Agricultural Development of Puerto Rico: Small farmer project in Puerto Rico, 1985 (Reel L-543)
  - L85-74: University of Witwatersrand Center for Applied Legal Studies: Conference on labor laws in South Africa, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-75: University of Witwatersrand: Training Black Journalists, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-79: Instituto de Investigaciones Economicas, Argentina: Government expenditures on agriculture in Latin America, 1985 (Reel L-520)
  - L85-80: Community Action for Legal Services: Parental care campaign, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-81: Peterson, Jacobs and Company: Fragility of the financial system, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-84: Steve Biko Foundation Trust: Foster self reliance and practical community development, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-88: Ford Foundation: Education and culture meeting in Bali, Indonesia 5/13-17/85, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-90: Ford Foundation: Stabilization and adjustment policies in developing countries, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-92: Ford Foundation: Hispanics and education - improving the learning experiences of Hispanic-American, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-93: Massachusetts Institute of Technology: Workshop on transfer of technology between U.S. and Japan, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-98: Iowa Citizens for Community Improvement: Study of socio-economic condition of small farm sectors in Iowa, 1985 (Reel L-543)
  - L85-99: American Water Foundation: Information log on education and research on irrigation technology, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-102: Ford Foundation: Agro-Forestry/Social Forestry Evaluation Study, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-105: Boston University: Development strategy and poverty in Southern Asia, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-106: Hunter College: Study of Israeli Farmers and their use of irrigation, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-108: University of Capetown Institute of Criminology: Battered and Abused women in South Africa, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-109: Harvard University: Nuclear psychology program, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-110:: A natural park of the Andes in Bolivia, 1985 (Reel L-502)
  - L85-112: Government of Bangladesh: Regional Symposium on water resources policy, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-114: Southern Regional Council: Project for community technology, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-116: The University of Arizona: Training of Indian resource managers, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-120: Ford Foundation: Programs for pre-school children, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-121: Project South Africa: Promote peaceful changes in South Africa, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-122: University of Cape Town: Training of black researchers at the Institute, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-129: International Bank for Reconstruction and Development: Irrigation development options and investments, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-131:: Proposal to write a book on strategy for peace and war, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-132: North Dakota State University: Rural policy research in the high plains states and North Dakota, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-133: America's Governors, Inc.: Agriculture focus, a program to raise the importance of agriculture on the national agenda, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-134: Ford Foundation: To participate in several meetings with grant makers water policy forum, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-135: Ford Foundation: Water management synthesis project, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-136: N.A.T.O. North Atlantic Treaty Organization: Travel and study award for Murray Feshbach, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-137: Council on Economic Priorities: Verification of Arms Control, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-141: Ford Foundation: Cholula, Mexico 1984 International Affairs Meeting, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-142: Educational Exchange Foundation: To train Indian Natural Resource Managers, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-144: Volunteers in Technical Assistance: Youth of Micro Computers in relief operations, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-146: Ford Foundation: Home gardens, third world countries, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-148: Atlantic Institute for International Affairs: International center for scholars in international relations, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-149: Human-Economic Appalachian Development Corp.: Self-help programs and educational programs to affect fundamental changes in their economic system, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-151: Harvard University: economics and security, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-152: Hudson Institute, Inc.: Study of political implications of the debt crisis for Brazil, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-153: Valley of a Thousand Hills, South Africa: Improve resources provided in rural secondary education, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-154: University of Natal: Establish a center for socio-legal studies (see PA 86-1040), 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-161: Ford Foundation: Establish a Jamaica Community Foundation, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-162: University of Pittsburgh: University of Havana/University of Pittsburgh exchange program, 1985 (Reel L-520)
  - L85-163: University of Nevada, Las Vegas: Establish new masters program in ethics and policy studies, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-164: National Bureau of Economic Research: Program development in field of defense economics, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-165: Friedrich Ebert Stiftung, Inc.: General Support, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-167: Harvard University: American military policy: consensus and dissension, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-168: Atlanta University: Study of black police chiefs, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-169: Columbia University: Commissions for a Just World Peace, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-170: Ford Foundation: Minorities and Women in International Affairs, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-171: Catholic Relief Services - United States Catholic Conference Incorporated: Development of agro-forestry programs, 1985 (Reel L-543)
  - L85-173: Community Trust Foundation of Mississippi: Establishments of a community foundation, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-174: Centre for New Democracy: Multi-partisan meeting of emerging leaders from the U.S. and Pacific rim nations, 1985 (Reel L-503)
  - L85-175: Pacific Institute for Public Policy Research: The new protectionism, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-176: Infant Formula Action Coalition, Minnesota: Monitoring of infant formula marketing compliance program, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-180: Ford Foundation: Native American Task Force, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-181: Mzamo Child Guidance Clinic, South Africa: Enhance secondary education for South African blacks, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-182: Sistren Theater Collective, Jamaica: Caribbean popular theater exchange program, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-183: Community Access, Inc.: Provide living facilities for homeless individuals who are experiencing mental illness, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-184: Black Thoughts Publications: Provide independent publishing house to black authors in South Africa, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-186: Midwest Women's Center: Begin process of enterprise development, as a means to building agency self-sufficiency, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-187: Syracuse University: Research on excellence in non-selective colleges, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-188: Catholic Relief Services - United States Catholic Conference Incorporated: Activities of the ecumenical working group in Africa, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-189: SACHED Advice and Legal Aid Service, England: Legal aid to black South Africans, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-190: Haitian Association of Voluntary Agencies: Support for H.A.V.A. projects, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-194: Egyptian Police Academy: Visit to U.S. to gain familiarization with innovative research and training programs for police personnel, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-200: Georgetown University: Support for Phase II of Hemispheric Migration Project, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-201: Center for National Security Negotiations: Conference on nuclear policy and arms control, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-202: Ford Foundation: Foreign implementation of comparable worth, 1985 (Reel L-504)
  - L85-203: American Civil Liberties Union Foundation (ACLU): Feasibility study to establish an endowment fund, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-205: Ford Foundation: Growth, development and employment task force, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-208: The Book Foundation, Florida: Funds to create a national human services day, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-209: Ford Foundation: Study of liability insurance and human services, 1985 (Reel L-524)
  - L85-210: Ford Foundation: Roundtable on micro-enterprise development, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-211: Atlantic Institute for International Affairs: Proposals for international relations fellowships and study of technology policy and the west, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-213:: Research on the Mexican financial system, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-219: State University of New York/New Paltz: Collect and disseminate human rights material in Africa, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-220: Detention Action Committee: Rehabilitate Torture Victims, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-222: Canadian Center for Arms Control and Disarmament: Research of North American air defense, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-224: Recreation Ranch, Inc.: Support for project on therapeutic recreation, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-227: U.S.A. for Africa: Long term development assistance in Africa, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-230: Hudson Institute, Inc.: Western European adjustment to structural economic problems, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-231: Columbia University: Support for the Institute of African Studies, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-233: International Center for Peace in the Middle East: Development of curriculum for education on co-existence, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-234: Ford Foundation: Research and public analysis, 1985 (Reel L-520)
  - L85-234: Ford Foundation: Research and public analysis, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-235: Ford Foundation: Participation in public affairs (see PA 88-152), 1985 (Reel L-520)
  - L85-236: Ford Foundation: Public information and awareness, 1985 (Reel L-520)
  - L85-237: Ford Foundation: Puerto Rico, 1985 (Reel L-520)
  - L85-238: Ford Foundation: Minority public policy impacts, 1985 (Reel L-520)
  - L85-242: Ford Foundation: re: Terrorism, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-243: Council on Foundations, Inc.: Program committee services/Bill Diaz, 1985 (Reel L-532)
  - L85-247: Statue of Liberty/Ellis Island Foundation, Inc.: Development of priority projects outlined in Ellis Island Educational and Cultural Development Fund, 1985 (Reel L-505)
  - L85-248: Ford Foundation: Aid to establish the international committee on East and Central European Publishing, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-250: Ford Foundation: Explorations of overseas development of community foundations, 1985 (Reel L-521)
  - L85-251: Independent Church Institute: Research on independent churches in Southern Africa, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-258: Indiana University: Creation of a documentation center on Haiti, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-260:: Trade Union Training, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-261: Tougaloo College: To develop more effective transfer programs for minority students with the UNCF and 2 and 4 year institutions, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-262: Partnership for Productivity International: Ivory Coast Investment Corp. small industry banking, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-265: Committee for National Security: Produce series of packets dealing with Soviet studies, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-266: National Academy of Sciences: Policy workshops with East European countries (see PA 865-0604), 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-273: Wittenberg University: U.S./European consultation on peace research in history, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-275: Georgetown University: economic database on East Europe and USSR, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-276: Ford Foundation: Jakarta meeting on common property resources, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-277: Ford Foundation: Solicit proposals from Universities-Colleges to improve the quality of undergraduate education in selected institutions, 1985 (Reel L-543)
  - L85-281: Working Women Education Fund: Video display terminal proposal, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-282: O.E.F. International Women Law and Development Project: Regional consolidation of efforts in Asia, Africa and Latin America, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-283: Ford Foundation: Project Development/Women's Issues, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-287: International Training Center for Water Resources Management, France: Training in urban water supply and sanitation, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-289: Ford Foundation: Dean's Grants in Literacy and the Liberal Arts, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-292: Oglala Lakota College: Access project for archives and special collections, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-294: Hudson Institute, Inc.: Proposal entitled: Implications of the Info. Revolution for Soviet Society, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-295: Rehab Project (Ohio): To revitalize neighborhood through home ownership achieved by maximizing private-sector participation, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-297: National Mutual Housing Network: Development of low-income limited equity housing cooperatives and mutual housing, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-298: Arab Development and Credit Co.: General Support, 1985 (Reel L-541)
  - L85-299: International Planned Parenthood Federation/Western Hemisphere Region: Gender, Work and Fertility: Social, economic and political impacts of women's business ownership in the formal economic sector in Latin America, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-302: Center for Rural Affairs, Nebraska: Study in Farm Financial Crisis, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-303: Rocky Mountain Institute: Rural Eeconomic Renewal and Water Project, 1985 (Reel L-521)
  - L85-307: Virginia Water Project: Conference on women and community water issues, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-308: Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships: Fellowships for a 5-year period in less or non-developed countries, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-310: National Academy of Sciences: Discussion of arms control and national security issues, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-311: Irving Crespi, and Assoc.: To prepare a published manuscript on the status of women in American society and their labor force participation, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-313: Industrial Health and Safety Educational Project, South Africa: Health and Society education programs for workers, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-314: New York University: International law program for small number of highly qualified students, 1985 (Reel L-506)
  - L85-315: Canadian Institute for International Peace and Security: General Support, 1985 (Reel L-506)
- 1986
  - L86-2: Foundation for International Conciliation (England): Mediation in South Africa, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-3: U.N.-Latin American Institute for Prevention of Crime and Treatment of Offenders (Costa Rica): Support for their programs, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-5: Ford Foundation: Mainland Puerto Ricans/ Community Foundation Project, 1986 (Reel L-541)
  - L86-6: Population Council (New York): Research in International Labor Migration, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-7: Options Institute: To pursue research and discussion about policy options for democratic South Africa, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-8: City University of New York, Brooklyn College: Conference on the implications for higher education of social constructionist thought, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-11: Techno Serve, Inc. (Norwalk, CT): Training and technical assistance to community based enterprises (rural), 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-13: U.S. Department of the Interior-Bureau of Indian Affairs: Arts programs - U.S. Department of the Interior-Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-15: Public-Private Ventures: VICI housing authority project, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-17: I. I. E. (New York): To help increase university participation in international careers and internship programs, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-19: Behavioral Technology Consultants, Inc. (Chevy Chase, MD): African relief and recovery assurance project, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-22: University of Cape Town: Conduct study of community experience of police action, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-23: MASI-FUNDE Educational Project (South Africa): Administrative and salary support for MASI-Funde, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-25: Overseas Development Institute Limited: Third World Fellowship Program, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-26: Tufts University (MASS): History and Humanities Center for Nuclear Age Studies, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-28: Institute for International Studies: Arms Industries and Arms Transfer in Developing World, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-31: Ford Foundation: Advisory Committee-Workforce 2000, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-34: Rhodes University: To provide legal information and support service in the Eastern Cape, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-37: Milwaukee Repertory Theatre: Non-traditional casting- minority actors, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-39: Ford Foundation: Compile info on awards program (for David Arnold), 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-40: Ford Foundation: Education Group: to discuss the scope of Foundation work in education and to consult on particular issues or proposals, 1986 (Reel L-516)
  - L86-42: Genesis Foundation: African related programs of mutual interest, 1986 (Reel L-516)